<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Making the Ordinary Extraordinary With Data Together</title>
    <link>https://sumant-28.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Making the Ordinary Extraordinary With Data Together</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 14:29:11 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sumant-28.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apple Health Data Lake in AWS – Odds and Ends</title>
      <link>https://sumant-28.github.io/posts/datalakept2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 14:29:11 +1300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sumant-28.github.io/posts/datalakept2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my previous blog post I described the process of using my Apple Health (AH) records collected over the course of many years and migrating it to a data lake. I omitted some details which I will address here. I may write another post later if I deem it worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;data-completeness&#34;&gt;Data completeness&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The earlier post only dealt with architecture and daily incremental ingest. However by itself it is almost useless to me as an end user. The real power of analytics comes with combining the most recent data with records collected years ago to make meaningful comparisons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementing an Apple Health data lake using AWS</title>
      <link>https://sumant-28.github.io/posts/awsdatalake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:27:50 +1300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sumant-28.github.io/posts/awsdatalake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the past I developed a solution to examine the Apple Health &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sumant-28/AppleHealthParser.jl&#34;&gt;data download&lt;/a&gt; exported as an xml file. Upon reflection that only served as a stepping stone to implementing a personal data lake. A serverless application hosted in the cloud allows for much more powerful use of the data with real time insights to drive day to day decision making.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have implemented the following solution in Amazon Web Services (AWS) which will form the basis of this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
